Tim Hordern

tim@timhordern.com

timhordern.com github.com/mence

I have more than 15 years of corporate experience in Australian and internationally through a variety of senior roles in tech companies and startups. I have worn many hats and can successfully lead Technical and Product teams as a Team Lead, Technical Lead, Engineering Manager or Product Manager. I help build better products with a product management, scalable growth, and quality-driven mindset. Sometimes I just do all the things. I enjoy working in small teams with fantastic people, building valuable products, on interesting technology, in the right culture. I prefer small startups or growth teams inside wider organisations where I can have an outsize impact.

I'm currently seeking Engineering Manager, Technical Lead or Team Lead opportunities in Melbourne, Australia or remote across Australia or Asia Pacific..

Work Experience

GreenSync

Head of Markets - Melbourne, Australia

- Product and Team Lead for deX Markets at GreenSync. I helped establish digital markets around the world for the trading and management of electrical assets on a cloud-based software platform.
- Designed and architected the Active Network Management integration and deX Market product for integration with UK Power Networks and Smarter Grid Solutions to help manage Distributed Energy Resources (DER).
- Helped design and architect contract types and structure within deX, to enable closed market procurement of energy resources in the trial with Simply Energy, SA Power Networks and Tesla Energy. Helped form and lead cross-functional team to deliver this highest priority delivery milestone. Led workshops with SAPN and Simply stakeholders to confirm process and agree on system behaviour.
- Recruited and onboarded team to build ANM integration product and Market platform. Faciliated team inception to get team up and running understanding the problem and ready to develop in under a fortnight.
- Product Manager of the Markets product suite. Defined roadmap and strategies for growing and building market integration and trading.

2018 – 2019 GreenSync

deX Team Lead - Melbourne, Australia

- Team Lead for GreenSync's Decentralised Energy Exchange (deX), a digital marketplace that changes the way electricity is produced, used, stored and traded.
- Designed and architected the network mediation functionality of our deX Vision product to allow distribution networks to monitor and analyse electrical asset and dispatch behaviour.
- Planned the development of the deX Vision product integration with Schneider Electric's Advanced Distribution Management System and an Australian distribution network organisation for a much deeper continuous electrical distribution network management process.
- Replatformed the deX Developer Centre to better suit developer needs, improve integration onboarding process, and assist internal teams in developing to the shared deX platform.

2017 - 2018 GreenSync

Delivery Transformation Team Lead / Hardware & Integrations Team Lead - Melbourne, Australia

- Team Lead for GreenSync's internal scaling/optimisation team. Expertise developed here led us to transitioning to centrally own hardware development and software integrations across GreenSync.
- Led product and operations redesign of Peak Response Unit (PRU) hardware unit for demand response to enable scaling and outsourced manufacturing, leading to the build of 100s of units enabling the primary revenue stream for GreenSync. One of these units currently enables Australia's largest standalone Virtual Power Plant (VPP).

2019

- Led standardisation of Procure-To-Deliver process for turnkey PRU hardware solution including 'Code-Driven' procurement/configuration, fully replacing manual processes.
- Designed and architected integration with Tesla GridLogic system and PowerWall 2, as well as metering providers.
- Managed and configured Google Cloud Platform (GCP) infrastructure, including as owner for 5+ primary systems.
- Primary site reliability engineer and on call and after hours responder for all GreenSync production infrastructure for over 12 months. My time as this role as well as continuing as an escalation point helped establish common patterns and solutions for incident response at GreenSync. I developed formal incident response process and systems for the technology team to help scale incident response at GreenSync from 2 developers to across the development team, as well as helping develop formal business continuity responses.
- Developed and implemented infrastructure as code for range of environments via Terraform & Chef using GCP, across GCE, GKE and IAM.
- Configured and managed alerting and notification infrastructure, including Datadog, PagerDuty, New Relic, Sentry, Pingdom and Stackdriver systems.
- Led security management and response including establishment of penetration tests and initial analysis of certification responses and answers.

2016 Spotify

QA Tester / Test Engineer - New York, NY

- Front-end developer for internal analytics visualisation project. Built React.js frontend rendering C3.js charts for Google BigQuery results. Implemented build system using Webpack, ESLint, and Karma. Helped build and deploy Jenkins continuous deployment (CD) infrastructure.
- Helped implement end to end Dockerized Selenium Java tests for Creator project.

2015 - 2016 XO Group

Lead Software Engineer in Test - New York, NY

- Lead Test Engineer for internal React.js app, building features, infrastructure, automation suites & the CI build system, after helping rescue original project. Helped shape user flows and built up library of React UI components to match designs.
- Built first Docker application using continuous delivery pipeline for content team. Built tooling to clone production apps & data into local Docker containers for a better development environment. Rebuilt Jenkins environments for faster feedback & smaller build queues.
- Ran first ever XO internal hackathon with 20 apps built, including one saving \$80k/year.
- Pushed to improve code quality, using developer pairing/coaching, building style guides & linters, and implementing improved testing practices & standards.

2013 - 2015 Intent Media

Agile QA Engineer - New York, NY

- QA Engineer & Product Analyst for first continuous delivery reporting tool, developing features, prioritised and scoped work, built prototypes and developed automated test suites.
- Performed functional testing on Intent's full stack which featured a combination of Javascript, Java, Rails, MySQL, Vertica, S₃, MongoDB, iOS, and backend Node applications. Built production test for service verification.
- Grew QA team, recruiting engineers, building performance test suites, and redefined practices & recruitment processes.

2011 - 2013 Thought Works

Senior Consultant - Melbourne, Australia

- Held a number of consultant QA Engineer / Tester roles, notably testing Ruby, Node, Android and iOS applications, developing test automation and conducting exploratory testing. Additionally, I built performance test suites, as well as managed and optimised Jenkins continuous integration systems. Internal advisor on iOS application automation and submission processes.
- Product Designer for a suite of iOS applications for over 30,000 government staff and public customers. Ran user testing of iOS applications with range of users, including in-situ user testing sessions. Designed wireframes and prototypes for iOS applications and information kiosks. Designed icons and UI, from wireframe sketches to Illustrator assets.

2010 Infosys

Technical Test Lead - Melbourne, Australia

• Test Manager for SAP SRM Upgrade project, leading onsite and remote testing teams.

2006 - 2009

Accenture

Consultant - Melbourne, Australia

- Worked with a number of Australian and multinational organisations through their transformations.
- Established and coordinated project management office (PMO), planned future project phase resourcing & activities for transformation of \$14bn mining company.
- Planned and delivered data migration effort for large SAP PM/MM upgrade, supporting maintenance of 11,000+ vehicles travelling more than 350 million kms. Managed team of developers, analysts and client SMEs. Built test strategy and conversions for SAP MM/PM upgrade.
- Test Analyst for Oracle RPM implementation and in-store & POS retail systems for supermarket chain, handling \$35 billion in transactions for 8.8 million consumers.

2003 - 2005

General Motors Holden

Analyst - Melbourne, Australia

- Reporting/System Analyst for SAP R/3 AP, invoicing and Procure-To-Pay processes.
- SAP SRM Analyst & System Administrator, developed and managed data in Requisite electronic catalogues, in conjunction with external vendors.
- Reporting and Database Analyst for procurement department, reporting directly to executive team and CEO. Developed and administered reporting toolsets and redeveloped key database to streamline end of month reconciliation.
- Delivered data migration and go-live capability for large SAP MM/SRM implementation. Led conversions team across multiple rollouts and managed data cleansing team.

Education

2014 - 2015

Product Management Course

General Assembly - New York, NY

2001 - 2005

Bachelor of Information Systems

University of Melbourne - Melbourne, Australia

Originally a double degree of Commerce and Information Systems. Graduated earlier with B.InfoSys to pursue work opportunities.

Further Information

Project Experience

More details of my consulting and work projects. This is a detailed listing of the projects/roles I've worked on/had.

Side Projects

Details of some side projects I've built

/nox

What I'm working on now